

Checkpoint Monitoring your cluster and applications

Monitoring:

*Monitor THE application ressources use (ram,cpu,memory) and traffic between components using(istio service mech (multi-containers pods))
    
> https://miro.medium.com/max/700/1*o1fn5I5VO2lWlOu6qv7TsQ.gif


 DeploymentConfig object:

apiVersion: apps.openshift.io/v1
kind: DeploymentConfig
metadata:
  name: helloDC
spec:
  replicas: 1
  selector:
      app: helloDC
  template:
    metadata:
      labels:
        app: helloDC
    spec:
      containers:
      - name: helloDC
        image: openshift/hello-openshift
        ports:
        - containerPort: 8080


#add  in  bold text
       annotations:
           sidecar.istio.io/inject: "true"
#

apiVersion: apps/v1
kind: Deployment
metadata:
  name: hello
spec:
  replicas: 1
  selector:
    matchLabels:
      app: hello
  template:
    metadata:
      labels:
        app: hello
      annotations:
        sidecar.istio.io/inject: "true"
    spec:
      containers:
      - name: hello
        image: openshift/hello-openshift
        ports:




**Monitor the cluster , node status, pods, deployment number, status … using prometheus and Grafana 


A Complete Introduction to Monitoring Kubernetes - New Relic
https://newrelic.com › platform › monitoring-guide
Whether you're a Kubernetes cluster admin, an application developer, ... Until recently, monitoring the performance of your Kubernetes clusters and the ...
People also ask
How do I monitor applications in Kubernetes?
Image result for monitor your cluster and your application.
Here are the most popular and most reliable open-source monitoring tools you can choose from when working with Kubernetes.

    Kubelet. ...
    Container Advisor (cAdvisor) ...
    Kube-state-metrics. ...
    Kubernetes Dashboard. ...
    Prometheus. ...
    Jaeger. ...
    Kubewatch. ...
    Weave Scope.

More items...

9 top open-source tools for monitoring Kubernetes | TechBeacon
https://techbeacon.com › enterprise-it › 9-top-open-source...
Search for: How do I monitor applications in Kubernetes?
What should I monitor in Kubernetes?


How do I monitor Kubernetes nodes?


Why Kubernetes monitoring is important?

What is KUBE proxy?
Image result

How does Kubernetes detect CPU and memory utilization?
If you want to check pods cpu/memory usage without installing any third party tool then you can get memory and cpu usage of pod from cgroup.

    Go to pod's exec mode kubectl exec pod_name -- /bin/bash.
    Go to cd /sys/fs/cgroup/cpu for cpu usage run cat cpuacct.usage.

More items...
•
Feb 5, 2019

Checking kubernetes pod CPU and memory - Stack Overflow
https://stackoverflow.com › questions › checking-kuberne...
Search for: How does Kubernetes detect CPU and memory utilization?
How do I check my Kubernetes performance?
You can examine application performance in a Kubernetes cluster by examining the containers, pods, services, and the characteristics of the overall cluster. Kubernetes provides detailed information about an application's resource usage at each of these levels.Oct 17, 2020

Tools for Monitoring Resources | Kubernetes
https://kubernetes.io › tasks › resource-usage-monitoring
Search for: How do I check my Kubernetes performance?
What is vCPUs?

What is CPU limit in Kubernetes?

How can Kubernetes improve performance?


How do I monitor k8s cluster?
Image result
The most straightforward solution to monitor your Kubernetes cluster is by using a combination of Heapster to collect metrics, InfluxDB to store it in a time series database, and Grafana to present and aggregate the collected information. The Heapster GIT project has the files needed to deploy this design.Mar 19, 2020

Kubernetes Monitoring: Best Practices, Methods, and Solutions - Logz.io
https://logz.io › blog › kubernetes-monitoring
Search for: How do I monitor k8s cluster?
What is KUBE monkey?

Which of the following is a cluster monitoring tool?
Our overview of container technology for cluster management tools includes Docker Swarm, CoreOS, Kubernetes and Apache Mesos.May 5, 2016

4 Cluster Management Tools to Compare - AppDynamics
https://www.appdynamics.com › blog › product › 4-cluste...
Search for: Which of the following is a cluster monitoring tool?
How do I check my Kubernetes cluster health?


How does Prometheus work?
Image result
Prometheus can scrape metrics from jobs directly or, for short-lived jobs by using a push gateway when the job exits. The scraped samples are stored locally and rules are applied to the data to aggregate and generate new time series from existing data or generate alerts based on user-defined triggers.

What is Prometheus and Why Should You Use It? | Opsani
https://opsani.com › resources › what-is-prometheus-and-...
Search for: How does Prometheus work?
What is a Beowulf cluster used for?
Image result

What are the applications of clustering in management?

What is the role of a cluster manager?
These agents run on each node of the cluster to manage and configure services, a set of services, or to manage and configure the complete cluster server itself (see super computing.) ... In some cases the cluster manager is mostly used to dispatch work for the cluster (or cloud) to perform.

Cluster manager - Wikipedia
https://en.wikipedia.org › wiki › Cluster_manager
Search for: What is the role of a cluster manager?
What companies use Prometheus?
661 companies reportedly use Prometheus in their tech stacks, including Uber, Slack, and Robinhood.

    Uber.
    Slack.
    Robinhood.
    Nubank.
    medium.com.
    Alibaba Travels.
    deleokorea.
    trivago.


Prometheus - Reviews, Pros & Cons | Companies using Prometheus
https://stackshare.io › prometheus
Search for: What companies use Prometheus?
Is Prometheus better than Nagios?
Image result
Prometheus and Nagios are very different in their designs, their audiences, and their capabilities. Prometheus is useful for monitoring app functionality, while Nagios is a very powerful platform for application networks and security. However, Prometheus has the edge in performance metrics.Jul 15, 2020

Prometheus vs Nagios | Logz.io
https://logz.io › blog › prometheus-vs-nagios-metrics
Search for: Is Prometheus better than Nagios?
What is the difference between Grafana and Prometheus?
Image result
Grafana and Prometheus, both help us in tackling issues related to complex data in a simplified manner. Grafana is an open-source visualization software, which helps the users to understand the complex data with the help of data metrics. ... Prometheus is an open-source event monitoring and alerting tool.Mar 6, 2020

Grafana vs. Prometheus: Complete Difference Explained - WisdomPlexus
https://wisdomplexus.com › blogs › grafana-vs-prometheus
Search for: What is the difference between Grafana and Prometheus?
What is the salary of cluster manager?
Cluster Manager Salaries
Job Title	Salary
OYO Cluster Manager salaries - 10 salaries reported	₹5,15,629/yr
Aditya Birla Group Cluster Manager salaries - 8 salaries reported	₹8,18,500/yr
Rivigo Cluster Manager salaries - 7 salaries reported	₹19,82,009/yr
Stanza Living Cluster Manager salaries - 7 salaries reported	₹8,00,000/yr
16 more rows

Cluster Manager Salaries - Glassdoor
https://www.glassdoor.co.in › Salaries › india-cluster-man...
Search for: What is the salary of cluster manager?
What is cluster and how it works?

What is a cluster role?

What is Prometheus good for?
Image result

Does Google use Prometheus?

What is advantage of Prometheus?

What is Thanos Prometheus?
Image result

Should I use Prometheus or InfluxDB?

Can splunk replace Nagios?

Does Splunk use Prometheus?

Is Grafana part of Prometheus?
Image result

Prometheus and Grafana can work together as following :

Prometheus acts as the storage backend and open source grafana as the interface for analysis and visualization. 
Prometheus collects metrics from monitored targets by scraping metrics from HTTP endpoints on these targets. 
Prometheus exposes a wide variety of metrics that can be easily monitored







#Prometheus configuration

scrape_configs:
  - job_name: kubernetes-nodes-cadvisor
    scrape_interval: 10s
    scrape_timeout: 10s
    scheme: https  # remove if you want to scrape metrics on insecure port
    tls_config:
      ca_file: /var/run/secrets/kubernetes.io/serviceaccount/ca.crt
    bearer_token_file: /var/run/secrets/kubernetes.io/serviceaccount/token
    kubernetes_sd_configs:
      - role: node
    relabel_configs:
      - action: labelmap
        regex: __meta_kubernetes_node_label_(.+)
      # Only for Kubernetes ^1.7.3.
      # See: https://github.com/prometheus/prometheus/issues/2916
      - target_label: __address__
        replacement: kubernetes.default.svc:443
      - source_labels: [__meta_kubernetes_node_name]
        regex: (.+)
        target_label: __metrics_path__
        replacement: /api/v1/nodes/${1}/proxy/metrics/cadvisor
    metric_relabel_configs:
      - action: replace
        source_labels: [id]
        regex: '^/machine\.slice/machine-rkt\\x2d([^\\]+)\\.+/([^/]+)\.service$'
        target_label: rkt_container_name
        replacement: '${2}-${1}'
      - action: replace
        source_labels: [id]
        regex: '^/system\.slice/(.+)\.service$'
        target_label: systemd_service_name
        replacement: '${1}'